Almost History... Almost Legends... Mostly Ridiculous.
Almost Heroes is a adventure, comedy, western
film directed by Christopher Guest.
Two hapless explorers lead an ill-fated 1804 expedition through the Pacific Northwest in a
hopeless, doomed effort to reach the Pacific Ocean before Lewis and Clark.
Bartholomew Hunt, played by Chris Farley.
Leslie Edwards, played by Matthew Perry.
Jonah, played by Bokeem Woodbine.
Sergeant, played by Barry Del Sherman.
Guy Fontenot, played by Eugene Levy.
Shaquinna, played by Lisa Barbuscia.
Almost Heroes is a 1998 American adventure comedy Western film directed by Christopher Guest, narrated by
Guest's friend and frequent collaborator Harry Shearer, and starring Chris Farley and Matthew Perry.
The film marked Farley's last leading film role and was released
posthumously, five months after his death in 1997.
Almost Heroes was produced by Turner Pictures and DiNovi
Pictures and released by Warner Bros.
on May 29, 1998.
The film received negative reviews from critics and was a box office
bomb, grossing $6.1 million against a $30 million budget.
The film explores themes of fight, bravery, native american,
slapstick comedy, interracial relationship.
The tone is lighthearted.